<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Erik's Electronics Projects</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Erik's Electronics Projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:07:36 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erik6K.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Storage Oscilloscope</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:07:36 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/</guid><description>
DSO on the test bench, sampling a 20 kHz sine wave. Individual design project completed for ELEN90053 Electronic System Design at the University of Melbourne. This DSO has a single channel capable of sampling up to 60 MS/s, with a variable-length memory buffer between 2 to 128 KB, software switchable +/- 2.5V, 5V, 12.5V, and 25V input stages with 240VAC protection, and an automatic calibration system.
Closeup of the DSO.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Musical Instruments</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:50:18 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/</guid><description>
Some of the modules I have designed. In my own time I develop and build modular synthesizer modules. I initially started this as a way to gain practical design experience that I was not getting from university, but it has become a personal passion of mine. Each module I set out to design and build brings its own set of challenges, research, surprises, and ultimately experience. I feel that this endeavour has given me a lot of intuition about the design process that I otherwise would not have.</description></item><item><title>SES Remote Monitor</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/ses-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:46:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/ses-monitor/</guid><description>
The remote monitoring hardware (grey) and a prototype antenna with amplifier for sensing the 240Vac (black). Project completed for the State Emergency Service Communications Unit, during CITS3200 Professional Computing at the University of Western Australia. During this unit, groups of students studying the Computer Science major were placed into university-sourced industry projects involving real clients.
The SES often has to respond to large scale bushfire emergencies in very remote locations, which are often radio blackspots.</description></item><item><title>Self-Driving Boat</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/boat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:28:04 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/boat/</guid><description>
The dissasembled boat, with 2 prototype control boards which had different compass IC&amp;rsquo;s mounted. Group project completed for ENSC3020 Digital Embedded Systems at the University of Western Australia. The task was to design a boat which would be placed at one side of a pool and, at power on, drive foward in as straight a line as possible until it detected an obstacle (opposite edge of the pool), at which point it would execute a 180 degree turn and then drive again in a straight line until it reached its starting position.</description></item></channel></rss>