<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Erik's Electronics Projects</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Erik's Electronics Projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:07:36 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erik6K.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Storage Oscilloscope</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:07:36 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/</guid><description>
Individual design project completed for ELEN90053 Electronic System Design at the University of Melbourne. The project brief was for a 40 MS/s single channel scope with a +/- 5V input range, fixed 64 KB acquisition buffer, DAC controllet trigger level, and a galvanically isolated serial over USB interface for PC data transfer.
The DSO I designed improves upon these specifications by providing a single channel capable of sampling at up to 60 MS/s, a variable-length memory buffer between 2 to 128 KB, software switchable +/- 2.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Musical Instruments</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:50:18 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/</guid><description>
In my own time I develop and build modular synthesizer modules. I initially started this as a way to gain practical design experience that I was not getting from university, but it has become a personal passion of mine. Each module I set out to design and build brings its own set of challenges, surprises, and ultimately experience. I feel that this endeavour has given me a lot of intuition about the design process that I otherwise would not have gained from university projects alone.</description></item><item><title>SES Remote Monitor</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/ses-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:46:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/ses-monitor/</guid><description>
Project completed for the State Emergency Service Communications Unit, during CITS3200 Professional Computing at the University of Western Australia. During this unit, groups of students studying the Computer Science major were placed into university-sourced industry projects involving real clients.
The SES must often respond to large scale bushfire emergencies in very remote locations, which are often radio blackspots. In these sitations, maintaining constant communication is vital, and so the SES Communications Unit (SES CSU) sets up remote radio repeaters to cover such blackspots.</description></item><item><title>Self-Steering Boat</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/boat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:28:04 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/boat/</guid><description>
The dissasembled boat, with 2 prototype control boards which had different compass IC&amp;rsquo;s mounted. Group project completed for ENSC3020 Digital Embedded Systems at the University of Western Australia. The challenge was to design a boat which would be placed at one end of a pool and, once powered, drive foward in as straight a line as possible (regardless of disturbances) until it detected the opposite edge of the pool.</description></item></channel></rss>