<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Erik's Projects</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Erik's Projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:07:36 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erik6K.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Storage Oscilloscope</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:07:36 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://erik6K.github.io/posts/dso/bench.jpg"/>
Individual design project completed for ELEN90053 Electronic System Design at the University of Melbourne. This DSO has a single channel capable of sampling up to 60 MS/s, with a variable-length memory buffer between 2 to 128 KB, software switchable +/- 2.5V, 5V, 12.5V, and 25V input stages with 240VAC protection, and an automatic calibration system. Closeup of the DSO.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Musical Instruments</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:50:18 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://erik6K.github.io/posts/modular/mods_front.jpg"/>
In my own time I develop and build modular synthesizer modules. I initially started this as a way to gain practical design experience that I was not getting from university, but it has become a personal passion of mine. Each module I set out to design and build brings its own set of challenges, research, surprises, and ultimately experience. I feel that this endeavour has given me a lot of intuition about the design process that I otherwise would not have.</description></item><item><title>SES Remote Monitor</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/ses-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:46:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/ses-monitor/</guid><description>
Project completed for the State Emergency Service, during xxxxxxx at the University of Western Australia in which groups of students studying the Computer Science major were placed into projects with real clients. etc&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Self-Driving Boat</title><link>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/boat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 21:28:04 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://erik6K.github.io/posts/boat/</guid><description>
Group project completed for xxxxxx at the University of Western Australia. I designed and assembled the hardware, and wrote firmware for the Arduino (C++). The firmware implemented a simple PI controller which stabilised the heading of the boat by independently controlling the speed of the boat&amp;rsquo;s two motors. Current heading data was obtained from a compass sensor IC, which communicated with the Arduino over I2C, using a premade library which processed the incoming data and returned an absolute bearing.</description></item></channel></rss>